DARIOS TEKLEMARIAM

CONTACT

Address : El Cerrito CA 94530 Phone : (415) 858-2107

Email:dariosteklemariam@gmail.com

LINKS

- https://dariosyo.github.io/Portfolio/
- · linkedin.com/darios-teklemariam
- github.com/dariosyo

SKILLS

- HTML
- CSS
- JavaScript
- MERN application
- · User Interface (UI) design
- · RESTful API development
- Video and sound Editing, Color Correction/Grading Knowledge
- Excellent work ethic, Teamwork, Responsible

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Solution-driven professional excelling in highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions to challenges and focused on customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS, JQuery, JavaScript and MERN stack on Frontend and Backend. Experience building products for app users, meeting highest standards for web design, user- experience, best practices, usability and speed. Responding to challenges by designing and developing solutions and building web applications aligned to customer's services. Translating solutions into code and working across many different APIs, third-party integrations and databases. Self-motivated Web Developer with high level of experience working on multiple projects. Passionate and hardworking with penchant for meeting deadlines. Interested in role with company promoting best practices and offering diverse customer projects.

WORK HISTORY

Autonomous Vehicle Test Operator, 09/2020 to Current **Cruise Automation Inc.** - San Francisco, CA

- Generated 10 or more daily reports to help with addressing design and production concerns.
- Completed skilled soldering, corrections and wiring tasks to produce high-quality work.
- Participated in continuous improvement by generating suggestions, engaging in problem-solving activities to support teamwork.
- Devoted special emphasis to punctuality and worked to maintain outstanding attendance record, consistently arriving to work ready to start immediately, 2 times of Employee of the month.
- Worked closely with senior operation leads to maintain optimum levels of communication to effectively and efficiently complete projects.
- Led projects and analyzed data to identify opportunities for improvement.

Freelance Videographer, 05/2013 to Current **ELDA Production** - San Francisco, CA

- Set up technical details of over 4 for shots, including lighting and sound.
- Set up for shots according to production schedules, weather and lighting conditions and available equipment.
- Produced original video content by working collaboratively with producers, designers and art specialists to facilitate multimedia production.
- Collaborated with over 5 team members to develop content and message of long footage.
- Used Final cut pro and Davinci Resolve to edit footage into correct order and add effects.

Application Developer, 01/2016 to 01/2019 **Portfolio Pizzeria** - Oakland, CA

- Developed and implemented personalized client solutions using HTML, CSS and JavaScript programming language expertise.
- Provided positive customer support training experience for completed applications.
- Designed new features for mobile apps such as QR code reader
- Provided code maintenance and system upgrades to maximize performance.
- Wrote code for database-driven applications.

Technical Support Specialist, 06/2009 to 06/2012 **USI Technologies Inc.** - Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

- Explained technical information in clear terms to non-technical individuals to promote better understanding.
- Followed up with clients to verify optimal customer satisfaction following support engagement and problem resolution.
- Documented all transactions and support interactions in system for future reference and addition to knowledge base.
- Developed and tested new product offerings prior to release to assist development team in bug identification.
- Configured hardware, devices and software to set up work stations for employees.
- · Activated accounts for clients interested in new services.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science: Management Information Systems, 06/2007 **Unity University** - Addis Ababa, Ethiopia

ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Resolved product issue through consumer testing.
- Collaborated with team of 6 in the development of new product.

CERTIFICATIONS

- Full-Stack Development, UC BERKELEY EXTENSTION, 2018
- Web Development Bootcamp, UDEMY, 52 HOURS
- React, UDEMY, 40 HOURS